《反恐24小时》前情提要
Previously on 24
不
No!
先生  是参议员迈尔
Sir,it's senator Mayer.
他遇害了
He is dead.
你是说  杰克·鲍尔
Are you telling me that Jack Bauer
杀了一位美国议员吗
just killed a united states senator?
你们怎么能让这种事发生
How could you have let this happen?!
卡宁先生  你别把这一切都怪在我头上
Mr. Kanin,you are not going to lay this one at my feet.
怎么了  伊桑  出什么事了
What is it,Ethan,what's wrong?
总统阁下  恐怕我别无选择
Madam president,i'm afraid i have no choice
只能辞去联席参谋长一职了
But to resign as your chief of staff.
你想的太多了
You're taking this too far.
杰克在哪
Where is Jack?
我们没有抓到他
We don't have him.
陷害鲍尔谋杀了伯内特的人叫约翰·奎恩
The man who framed Jack for Burnett's murder was John Quinn,
他是斯塔克伍德的一名雇佣兵
a Starkwood contractor.
杰克到迈尔那边取证
Jack went to Mayer to get the evidence to prove it.
斯塔克伍德和今天
Starkwood was involved with everything
发生的一切都有关联
That's happened today. they were the ones
是他们协助朱玛一伙撞毁飞机并袭击白宫
That helped Juma and his men bring down the plane and attack the White House.
作为交换  他们获准在桑加拉
In exchange,they were allowed to develop
研发并生产大规模杀伤性武器
And manufacture a WMD in Sangala.
我从他们手下的手机里获取的短信
The text message i got off their agent's cell phone
显示  "亚历山大港  晚上10点50分"
Said "port of Alexandria, 10：50 p.m."
-警报  警报  -打  打
- Go red,go red! - Engage,engage.
快把车开走
Get that truck out of here now!
托尼  我去追卡车
Tony! the truck-- I'm going after it!
掩护我
Cover me now!
我这有在亚历山大港
I'm in possession of a biological weapon
截获的生化武器
Interdicted at the port of alexandria.
你那边情况如何
What's your status?
武器到手了  我们在返回途中
Package is secure; we're inbound.
鲍尔呢
What about Bauer?
但他躲到了附近的掩体
But he sought cover nearby.
我们得假定他通知了当局
We have to assume that he contacted the authorities,
我们要加快进度了
So we'd better be on an accelerated timetable.
快过来
Get over here.
斯塔克伍德重新夺回了生化武器
Starkwood reacquired the bioweapon.
并把武器空运走了
They airlifted the freight right out of here.
他们从我这的位置往正西方走了
They were headed due west from my current position.
杰克  我不能攻击私人领地
Jack,i can't assault a private compound
除非我有他们持有生化武器的证据
Unless i have proof that a weapon exists.
好吧  疾病控制中心的人呢
Okay,where is the CDC?
他们在紧急召集一队人马
They're scrambling a team right now.
把他们派到我这来
Send them to me.
这有你要的证据
You'll have all the proof you need.
我暴露其中了
I was exposed.
以下情节发生在晚间11点至12点间
The following takes place between 11 p.m. and 12 a.m.
我们准备好了  先生  跟我来
We're ready for you,sir,come with me.
鲍尔先生
Mr. Bauer.
我是梅瑟尔医生  疾病控制中心的
Dr. Macer,CDC.
请你把衣服脱掉
We need you to get undressed.
你就是那位跟莫斯沟通过的人吧
You're the one that talked to agent Moss?
他跟我说了你的情况
He brought me up to speed,
说你掌握了有关生化武器的线索
Said you had some information about the bioweapon.
我只知道武器在桑加拉开发
All i know is that it was developed in Sangala,
据村子里的传闻说  武器正在实验
And according to rumors from the village that it was tested on,
所有的受害者都得了痴呆症或者瘫痪
All the victims suffered from dementia and paralysis.
检查神经媒介物和病原体
Check neurological vectors and pathogens.
泄露了多少
How much was released?
具体不清楚
I'm not exactly sure.
武器都储存在加压罐里
The weapon was stored in a pressurized canister.
在我封闭它之前
It was breached for maybe two minutes
大概泄露了2分钟
Before i could seal it off.
这不是感染后反应
This is not a reaction.
这是以前的旧伤疤
I've had these scars.
这是一种全谱抗生素
This is a full spectrum antibiotic.
它可以抑制各种已知的病原体
It should counteract a wide range of known pathogens.
走到这里来  先生
Step inside,sir.
抬起胳膊  闭上眼
Raise your arms and close your eyes.
詹尼斯  进展怎么样
Janis,where are we?
首府警局关闭了236高速6英里长的范围
Metro closed down a six-mile stretch of highway 236.
疾病控制中心第一反应小组到达了现场
The CDC first responders are on-site.
-到底怎么回事  -有一罐生化武器泄露了
- What the hell's going on? - One of the bioweapon canisters was breached.
杰克可能已被感染了
Jack may have been exposed.
-天哪  -斯塔克伍德拿走了毒气罐
- Oh,my god. - Starkwood took the canisters.
他们可能带着托尼·阿尔梅达和武器
They're probably flying it back to their main compound
一起飞回到位于弗吉尼亚的总部了
In Virginia,along with Tony Almeida.
-阿尔梅达  -对  他和杰克一起干
- Almeida? - Yeah,he was working with Jack.
我们估计他已被扣为人质了
We think he might have been taken captive.
等一下  我要你做一份
Hang on one second. i need you to put together
有关斯达克伍德的简报
A briefing packet on Starkwood.
我要每个部门都明白
I want every division caught up to speed
我们在跟什么人物较量
On what we might be dealing with.
你要对斯塔克伍德采取行动吗
You planning to move on Starkwood?
那地方太大了  实际上就是个军事基地
That place is enormous; it's practically a military base.
在疾病控制中心给出确凿证据前
We're not going to do anything till we have concrete evidence
我们不会采取任何行动的
on the bioweapon from CDC.
然后我会请示总统
Then i'll inform the president.
由她决定如何行事
She'll decide how to proceed.
阿尔梅达不会开口的
Almeida's not going to talk.
他不是孬种  他是个硬汉
He's not the type; he's the brave type.
知己知彼  百战不殆
Know the psychology of your subject.
这是我们的行事准则
That's in our manual.
走吧
Here we go.
霍奇斯先生
Mr. Hodges,
我们已经把泄露的罐子隔离开了
We isolated the damaged canister.
很走运
We got lucky.
他们知道我们手上有武器
They know we have the weapons.
这就糟糕了
That's not so lucky.
多久能准备就绪
How fast can you have them ready?
至少得2小时
It's going to take me at least two hours.
-太久了  汤姆  -先生  我们还不知道
- Too long,Tom. - Sir,we don't know
政府掌握了多少
What the government knows.
他们正在行动  而且会
They're coming,and they'll be coming
拿着所掌握的证据找上门来
With everything they've got,
唯一能制止他们的办法
and the only thing that's going to stop them
就是部署好这些武器
is getting these weapons ready to deploy.
是的  先生  我会尽全力
Yes,sir,i'll do my best.
我知道你会的
I know you will.
好了  出发
Okay,let's go!
联邦调查局都知道什么
What does the FBI know?
我不会再跟你啰嗦
I'm not going to ask you again.
好了
Okay.
你是好样的  托尼
You're a good man,Tony.
我知道你的背景
I know your profile.
我知道你难对付
You've had some hard breaks.
我也不想伤害你
I don't want to see you hurt,
所以你只要告诉我联邦调查局
So you just tell me what the FBI knows
掌握了多少我们的情况
About what we're doing here,
我不能保证你会笑着走出去
And i can't say you'll walk away smiling--
那是不现实的
That would be unrealistic--
但我会给你一条生路
But you'll be alive.
听清楚了吗
You hear me?
可我什么也不知道  霍奇斯先生
But i don't know anything,Mr. Hodges.
我是在给你机会  托尼
I'm giving you a way out,Tony.
先生
Sir,
我能跟你说两句吗
May i speak to you for a moment?
现在不行  格雷格
Not now,Greg.
拜托了  先生  就一会儿
Please,sir, Just for a moment.
什么事
What is it?
这本该是一次秘密行动
This was supposed to be a covert operation.
现在已经变样了
That is not the case anymore
政府已经知道我们拥有这些武器
The government knows that we have these weapons,
他们是不会不闻不问的
And they're not just going to sit on that information.
你怎么看  格雷格
What are you suggesting,Greg?
也许我们应该趁还来得及
Maybe we should destroy the evidence
把证据都销毁
While we still have some time.
真不敢相信
I can't believe
这话是从你嘴里说出来的
That i'm hearing this from you.
我只想帮把手  先生
I'm just trying to help,sir.
我跟你一样在乎这个公司
I care about this company as much as you do.
我深表怀疑
Oh,i doubt that.
为了得到这些武器  我们已经付出了
We've invested a lot of blood and treasure
太多金钱和血的代价
To get these weapons,
我是不会罢手的
And i'm not going to give them up.
想想你冒的风险  先生
Think about what you're risking,sir--
一切  所有你打下的江山
Everything,everything you've built.
你说你是要帮忙
You say you're trying to help.
知道我怎么想吗
You know what i think?
我看你就只担心自己的小命
I think you're worried about your own ass.
把他带出去  该用刑时就用刑
Get him out of here and do what you have to do.
小伙子  想想我跟你说的话
Think about what i said,young man.
你有点紧张了  格雷格
You're a little nervous,Greg.
我有条大新闻透露给你
Well, I've got a news flash.
其实我们都紧张
We're all nervous.
省省你那点优柔寡断吧
Keep your doubts to yourself.
不用我再提醒你了
I'm not going to tell you again.
我们要提取更多的血液和唾液样本
We're going to need to take more blood and saliva samples,
还要收集脑脊液样本
And i'd like to collect a spinal fluid specimen.
在我们得出结论之前  你必须被隔离
Until we know what we're dealing with, we need to keep you under quarantine.
还要多久才能知道  我有没有被感染
How long is it gonna be till you know whether or not I've been infected?
初步结果应该会在15分钟后出来
We should have the preliminary results in the next 15 minutes.
-好的  -梅瑟尔医生
- Okay. - Dr. Macer,
我们在空气中监测到微量病原体
We've detected trace amounts of an airborne pathogen.
主要集中在卡车附近
It's concentrated near the truck.
在周围环境中也有发现
We're also picking it up in the surrounding environments
但是浓度很低
At much lower concentrations.
能确定是什么物质吗
Can you identify it?
还不能  但我们正在分析样本
No,but we're analyzing a sample now.
这种小程度的扩散应该不会
These levels shouldn't present any danger
威胁到附近的人群
To the nearby population,
但还是要对大气实施监控
But I still want atmospheric monitors set up.
鲍尔先生  你封闭毒气罐真是太明智了
It's a good thing you sealed off the canister,Mr. Bauer.
你救了很多人的命
You saved a lot of lives.
还要麻烦你们把我送回调查局
You're going to have to transport me back to FBI.
我还是目前恐怖袭击的关键人证
I'm still material evidence in an ongoing terrorist threat.
这正是我们的使命  那边也能进行检测
Those were our orders. We can run our tests from there.
好的
Okay.
鲍勃·杰斯曼在过去3年
Bob Justman's been associate counsel
一直是助理咨询顾问
For the past three years.
他和伊桑在工作上关系很密切
He and Ethan worked very closely together.
担当联席参谋长他肯定够格
He is certainly qualified to be chief of staff.
但是
But
经过今天的事
After what's happened today,
我觉得你应把眼光放到内阁成员之外
I think you should be looking outside your administration.
内部成员能助我一臂之力
An insider has a leg up.
联席参谋长可是个极富挑战的职位
Chief of staff has a steep learning curve.
我觉得你是低估了新视角的价值
I think you're underestimating the value of a fresh perspective.
你心中已有人选了吧
You have someone in mind.
是的
I do.
瑞克·伯曼
Rick Berman.
瑞克会考虑离开他自己的私营企业吗
Would Rick even consider leaving the private sector?
他已经赚了很多钱了
Well,he's made his fortune.
我想他现在很想找个机会为国效力
I think he'd jump at the chance to serve his country.
我们找他谈谈吧
Let's sit down with him.
好啊
Great.
不过还是要再考虑一下鲍勃
But keep Bob on the list.
我仍觉得他是不错的人选
I still have a good feeling about him.
我明天就去安排会面
I'll start to set up meetings Tomorrow.
利维  想找能接替伊桑的人恐怕还要几周
Livy,it could take weeks to find Ethan's replacement.
在这段时间里
In the meantime,
我还需要一个代理参谋长
I'm going to need a provisional chief of staff.
我想任命你
I'd like that to be you.
什么事
Yes?
-蒂姆·伍兹要见您  -过几分钟之后
- Tim Woods is here to see you. - Just give me a minute,please.
-再让他进来 -是  阁下
- And then send him in. - yes ma’am.
利维  我需要一个可以信得过的人
Livy,I need someone I can trust.
特别是经历过今天发生的种种后
Especially after everything that's happened today.
你不会拒绝你的母亲的  对吧
You're not going to say "no" to your mother,are you?
当然不会
Of course not.
很好
Good.
总统阁下  调查局的拉里·莫斯
Madam president,I have Larry Moss
有电话找您
At FBI calling for you.
他有什么事
What's this about?
具体情况我也不知道
I don't know the specifics,
但他说是事关即将威胁国家安全的紧急事件
But he says it involves an imminent homeland threat.
接进来
Put him through.
没关系的  蒂姆
It's all right,Tim.
我刚任命奥利维亚为代理参谋长
I've made Olivia acting chief of staff.
莫斯探员  请讲
Agent Moss,you're on with the president.
总统阁下  我们取得了一些进展
Madam president,we have a situation developing.
首先  杰克·鲍尔没有杀
First of all,you need to know that Jack Bauer
莱恩·伯内特和参议员布莱恩·迈尔
Did not kill Ryan Burnett nor Senator Blaine Mayer.
他是被陷害的
He was framed for their murders.
我就知道是这样
I knew it.
-是谁干的  -根据我们的战术推断
- Who framed him?  - Our operational theory
他是被斯塔克伍德公司设计陷害的
Is that he was set up by Starkwood.
我不明白  为什么他们要栽赃嫁祸于杰克
I don't understand. why would Starkwood frame Jack?
他们是企图掩盖曾经协助朱玛
To cover up the fact that they helped Juma stage
策划了今天的恐怖袭击一事
The terrorist attacks today.
什么
What?
阁下  我们有证据表明
Ma'am,we have evidence
斯塔克伍德曾向朱玛
That Starkwood provided Juma
提供技术支持和内部情报
With technological support and intelligence.
而作为回报  朱玛允许他们在桑加拉
And in return,Juma allowed Starkwood to use Sangala
建设实验基地
As a base to operate without having
而且不用担心受到监管
To worry about any oversight.
作为什么的基地
A base for what?
制造大规模杀伤性武器
To manufacture weapons of mass destruction.
确切地说  是生化武器
Specifically,biological weapons.
你说的是哪种生化武器
What kind of bioweapons are you talking about?
我们还不确定  很可能是
We're not sure,but it could be
某种神经性病原体
Some kind of neurological pathogen.
疾病控制中心已拿到样本正在进行分析
CDC has obtained a sample and they're analyzing it now.
莫斯探员  你刚说有威胁正在逼近
Agent Moss,you said there was an imminent threat.
是的  一批生化武器
Yes,a large shipment of bioweapons
已经交货给了斯塔克伍德
Was delivered to Starkwood.
我们认为他们现在持有这些武器
We believe they're in possession of them now.
你是说这些武器就在美国本土吗
Are you saying these weapons are on U.S. soil?
我们猜测这些武器就在
We suspect they're at the Starkwood
斯塔克伍德的弗吉尼亚总部
Headquarters in Virginia.
你不认为斯塔克伍德
You're not suggesting that Starkwood
会使用这些武器来攻击我们的国家吗
Intends to use those weapons to attack this country?
还不清楚  但照他们今天的行动来看
We don't know,but,given their actions today,
我们必须马上对斯塔克伍德采取措施
We need to move on Starkwood immediately.
总统阁下
Madam President?
召集内阁成员和联席参谋长们
Assemble the cabinet and the joint chiefs.
是的  阁下
Yes,ma'am.
杰克是对的  斯塔克伍德的确有问题
Jack was right about Starkwood.
你也找到了他们协助朱玛的证据了吧
You found evidence that they've been supporting Juma.
是的
Yeah.
查出动机了吗
Did you find out why?
我是说  他们能从朱玛那捞到什么好处呢
I mean,what could Starkwood possibly get from Juma?
开发和测试生化武器的基础设施
The infrastructure to develop and test biological weapons.
我们认为这些武器就藏匿在
We think they're holding them somewhere
斯塔克伍德军事基地里
On the Starkwood compound.
好吧  杰克在哪
Okay,where's Jack?
在来调查局的路上
He's on his way over here.
怎么了  拉里
What,Larry?
他试图保护武器不被夺走  但
He managed to secure the weapons,but then,uh,
斯塔克伍德还是抢了回去
Starkwood got them back.
而与此同时
And when that happened,um...
杰克暴露在毒气中
Jack was exposed.
他可能被感染了
He may have been infected.
现正被隔离着
He's being placed under quarantine.
他在来这的路上  我们要让他说出
Listen,he's on his way here and we need to find out
他知道的所有关于这些武器的事
Everything that he learned about these weapons.
我想应该由你来给他做笔录
And I think you should be the one who debriefs him.
还有  我要向你道歉
And I owe you an apology.
我不该不信任你
I was wrong not to trust you,
我  我被自己对鲍尔的偏见蒙蔽了双眼
And I-I let my prejudice about Bauer get in the way.
但是
But
蕾妮  你也不该瞒着我
Renee,you should've kept me in the loop.
你应该相信我
You should've trusted me.
我知道
I know.
我是该相信你
I should have.
我们什么时候开始对斯塔克伍德采取行动
When are we moving on Starkwood?
亚伦
Aaron?
我待会儿再找你们办登记  好吗
I'll check in with you guys later,okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
我能跟你谈一谈吗
May I speak with you for a moment?
当然可以  我听说你
Of course. I heard you finished
已经做好笔录准备离开了
Your debrief and were on your way out.
是的  女士
Yes,ma'am.
我要你留下来
Well,I need you to stay.
什么
Ma'am?
我被任命为代理联席参谋长
I've been appointed acting chief of staff.
特勤组要安排一个探员
Secret service is going to assign an agent
负责我的安全事宜
To handle my security detail.
我希望由你来担此重任
I'd like that to be you.
真是非常荣幸  女士
Well,I'm truly flattered,ma'am,
但是你知道  我已经告老还乡了
But as you know,I'm retired.
我可以让你官复原职
I can have you reinstated.
还有大把大把的优秀的探员任你挑选
There are plenty of fine agents on the roster.
但我不想要他们
But I don't want them.
我只想用你
I want you.
我现在不能透露太多细节
I can't go into the details now,
但是对我们国家的威胁还远没有结束
But the threat to this country isn't over.
我们仍身处危机之中
We're in the middle of a crisis,
我需要信得过的人在我身边
And I need people around me I can trust.
我信任你  亚伦
I trust you,Aaron.
我不轻易对别人说这句话
I can't say that about a lot of people.
我马上还要参加总统的会议
I'm running into a meeting with the president.
姑且先认为你答应了
I'll assume your answer is "yes."
先生们  女士们  请就座
Gentlemen,ladies,please take your seats.
是  阁下
Yes ma'am
现在谁还没有读完简报的
Now,those of you who haven't had a chance to finish your briefing packets,
请继续
Please keep reading.
我们也是刚刚得知
As we've all just learned,
惊心动魄的一天还没有结束
This day is not over.
国家安全依然受到威胁
Our national security is still being threatened,
召集大家来是要考虑一下我们能做的选择
And we are here to consider our options.
伍兹先生
Mr. Woods.
各位的简报材料中
Your briefing materials
包括联邦调查局得到的一份情报
Include FBI intelligence about a cache
称生化武器藏匿在斯塔克伍德
Of biological weapons on Starkwood's main compound
位于北弗吉尼亚州的总部里
In northern Virginia.
这是该基地的近期卫星图像
This is a recent satellite view of the compound.
面积超过3平方英里  259个建筑物
Over three square miles,259 structures--
武器可能藏在那的任何地方
The weapons could be hidden anywhere on the facility.
是什么样的生化武器
What kind of bioweapons are we talking about?
这位是本·兰德利  疾病控制中心主任
This is ben landry,he's director of CDC.
他将就有关病原体的问题
He's here to answer any questions you may have
作出回答  本  请说吧
In regards to the pathogen. Ben.
我刚从外勤探员那里
I've just received a preliminary report
收到一份初步报告
From our agents in the field.
经他们鉴定  该病原体为朊病毒变体
They've identified the pathogen as a prion variant
是刚果东部特有的一种病毒
Indigenous to the east congo.
是克雅氏病症的一种形式
It's a form of creutzfeldt-jakob disease.
该病毒会侵染大脑和神经系统
It attacks the brain and the nervous system,
造成痴呆  体质下降
Causes dementia,physical deterioration,
并最终死亡
Ultimately death.
未变异的克雅氏病毒会在几个月内致死
Standard CJD kills within several months,
但这一变种致死速度更快
But this strain kills more quickly.
多久
How long?
一天  或许两天
A day,maybe two.
目前该疾病是不治之症  无药可医
There's no treatment for this disease. There's no cure.
若扩散到人口稠密的地区
If dispersed over a populated area,
后果将是灾难性的
The results would be catastrophic.
但不用我多说
But it goes without saying
我们绝不允许私人武装力量
We cannot allow a private military force,
这些刽子手们  拥有大规模杀伤性武器
These killers,to possess weapons of mass destruction.
我们要找到这些武器
We need to find these weapons,
逮捕斯塔克伍德的那群混蛋
And arrest those bastards in Starkwood
是他们把生化武器带到这里来了
Who are responsible for bringing them here.
总统阁下
Madam president.
考虑到基地的大小  我们将
Given the size of the compound,it would take
花费大量兵力去找出武器的位置
A considerable force to locate these weapons.
更不用提那里还有
Not to mention the fact that
1500名训练有素的雇佣兵
there are 1,500 highly-trained mercenaries on that base.
但愿他们不会武力抵抗
God forbid they decide to resist.
但愿不必后院起火  硝烟四起
We could have a small war in our own backyard.
总统阁下  我同意上述观点
I share those concerns,madam president.
我们也应该考虑到
We also have to consider the possibility
对方有使用生化武器对抗我们的可能性
That Starkwood might use these biological weapons against our own forces.
用空中打击如何
What about an air strike?
打击如此大规模的设施需要反复轰炸
A facility that large would require multiple bombing runs.
这就可能造成该基地内伤亡惨重
We'd be looking at massive casualties on the Starkwood base,
却不能确保是否能摧毁那批武器
With no guarantee of destroying the bioweapons.
据我们所知  武器可能埋在地下
For all we know, they've been buried underground
或者藏在加强型防御工事里
Or in fortified facilities.
如果打击力量不够强
There's also a risk that hitting these weapons
也有可能会造成那些生化剂
With insufficient force could release the bio-agent
被释放进大气里
Into the atmosphere.
我们不能无视法律
We can't just ignore the law here.
前面提到的所有方案
All these scenarios would be in violation
都有可能触犯了警卫团法案
Of the posse comitatus act.
我的意思是  我们不能
I mean,we can't deploy military personnel
在国会没有同意的情况下
In a law enforcement capacity.
以执法部门的名义部署武装人员
Not without congressional approval.
我听到的是
What i'm hearing
我们没有好的选择
Is that there are no good options.
我无法接受
I don't accept that.
除非我们找到控制这次危机的方法
Until we find a way to contain this threat,
否则我们的国家可能会遭遇另一次袭击
We are risking another attack on this country.
而我是不会考虑这样的选择的
And that is an option i won't consider.
霍奇斯先生想知道
Mr. Hodges wants to know
你有没有考虑过他的提议
If you've given any thought to his offer.
为什么你还要对一个背弃你的政府效忠呢
Why this loyalty to a government that screwed you over?
我搞不懂
I don't get it.
只要你告诉我们
Just tell us
调查局了解的情况  你就可以走了
What the FBI knows and you can walk.
告诉你吧
For the record,
我跟霍奇斯先生打赌你不会开口
I bet Mr. Hodges a pair of redskins tickets
赌注就是华盛顿红皮队的两张球票
You wouldn't talk.
看来离赛场仅50码距离的
Looks like i'm going to be sitting
好座位非我莫属了
On the 50 yard line.
到底发生什么事了
Hey,what the hell's going on?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我的帮助
My help?
我们得阻止这一切  事情进行得太过了
We need to stop this. it's gone too far.
除非你告诉我你为什么这么干
Look,i'm not going anywhere
否则我哪都不去
Until you tell me why you're doing this.
我不想因为乔纳斯·霍奇斯的疯狂行为
I'm not spending the rest of my life
而在监狱里过下半辈子
In prison because Jonas Hodges has lost his mind.
你知道武器在哪里吗
You know where the weapons are?
是的
Yes.
你最好现在就告诉我
Then you better tell me right now.
我想要豁免权
I want immunity.
听着  我无法给你承诺什么
Look,i can't promise you anything.
但我们可以给调查局打电话做笔交易
We can call the FBI and negotiate a deal,
他们给你豁免权
Immunity in exchange for your help
你就帮他们找到武器  我只能做这么多
In recovering the weapons,that's the best i can do.
我可以在我办公室里建立安全线路
I can set up a secure landline in my office.
好  走吧
Good,let's go.
我们现在回联邦调查局
We're pulling up to FBI.
我们得让你先待在这个隔离箱里
We have to put you in an isolation suit
然后才能把你送到隔离区里
To transfer you to the quarantine area.
我知道
I understand.
感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
没什么不同
No different.
鲍尔先生的血液检查结果出来了
We have the results of Mr. Bauer's blood work.
谢谢
Thank you.
开门
Open it.
谢谢
Thank you.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
拉里让我告诉你
Larry wanted me to tell you,
疾病控制中心的人带杰克·鲍尔来了
That CDC arrived with Jack Bauer.
我会在楼下隔离区见他们
I'll meet them down in quarantine.
他不在隔离区
he's not in quarantine.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我知道的就这么多
That's all i know.
他们刚通过安检  他正上楼
They just cleared security. he's on his way up.
杰克  你好吗
Jack,are you okay?
我的血液检查结果是阳性
My blood work came back positive.
我被感染了
I'm infected.
鲍尔先生  你可以在那间屋里换衣服
Mr. Bauer,there's a room for you to change in.
谢谢
Thank you.
没事
It's fine.
他并没待在隔离区里
But he's not in quarantine.
我们了解到这种病并不传染
We've learned the disease isn't contagious.
病毒被这么设计的原因是防止
It was engineered that way to prevent blowback
传播病毒的人受到感染
On the people deploying it.
但你们一定可以想到办法来救他
Okay. But there has to be something that you can do to help him.
无药可医
There's no cure.
但他是第一个感染者
But he's patient zero.
我们需要做进一步的实验
Whatever we learn from the pathogen
来了解病原体的信息
Will come from the tests we still need to run.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
我是梅瑟尔
This is Macer.
他现在情况稳定
He's stable for the moment.
请进
Yeah.
杰克
Jack,um...
我不知道说什么才好
I don't know what to say.
那就告诉我莫斯在斯塔克伍德上的进展吧
Then tell me that agent Moss followed up on Starkwood.
抱歉
Sorry.
拉里向白宫汇报了情况
Larry debriefed the White House
我们正等总统决定行动方针
And we're waiting on the president to decide on a course of action.
很好
Good.
有托尼的消息没
Any word on Tony?
抱歉  目前还没任何消息
Sorry,we don't know anything yet.
我要询问你有关
I need to debrief you
你所看见的毒气罐的情况
On the canisters that you saw.
你没事吧
You okay with that?
没事
Yeah.
我看到了港务局警察的口供
I read the statement from the port authority cop.
他说你为了救他
He said that you risked the mission
差点让整个行动功亏一篑
To save his life.
你做得对
You did the right thing.
谢谢
Thanks.
是实验室打来的
Uh,it's the lab.
也许是霍奇斯
It's probably Hodges.
我们得接电话
We should talk to him.
打开免提
Put it on speaker.
我是西顿
Seaton.
你究竟到哪里去了
Where the hell have you been?
我一直在找你
I've been trying to reach you.
我在看阿尔梅达这里的情况
I was,uh,checking on Almeida.
斯多克斯让他开口了吗
Did stokes get him to talk?
他还在进行  先生
He's still working on that,sir.
我告诉他  如果阿尔梅达不开口
I told him to put Almeida down
就把他干掉
If he didn't start talking.
我觉得应该多给他些时间  先生
I think we should give him a few more minutes,sir.
我们正忙着在政府行动之前
We're busting our asses to get these weapons ready
部署好这些武器
Before the government makes their move,
大家都要时刻准备
I want all hands on deck.
我马上就来 先生
We'll be there soon,sir.
那就快点来吧  格雷格
See that you are,Greg.
打电话给调查局
Call FBI.
我要设一个保密线路
I need to set up the secure landline.
确保没人可以窃听
Make sure nobody's listening.
好的  快点干吧
All right,well,do it.
从没想到乔纳斯会走到这个地步
I never thought Jonas would take it this far.
他是一个爱国者
I mean,the man's a patriot.
他成立斯塔克伍德是为了保护这个国家
He founded Starkwood to protect this country.
那他怎么还会发动这场袭击呢
Yeah,well,why is he attacking it?
原因很复杂的
It's complicated.
我也不了解
I don't understand it myself.
我应该尽自己的全力阻止这次袭击的
I should've done more to stop this.
我本应几个月前就报告调查局的
I should've called FBI months ago.
你现在这么做是对的
Well,you're doing the right thing now.
我把所有关于斯塔克伍德的信息全调出来了
I've pulled together everything we have on Starkwood.
建筑结构明细  航摄图
Structural specs,aerial maps,
还有公司的地形和人员名册
Topography,company roster,
-全部资料  -好的
- The whole works. - all right.
上传到部门间互联服务器上
Upload it onto the inter-agency servers.
让大家都看到调查进度
Let's get everybody on the same page.
干得好  詹尼斯
That's good work,janis.
蕾妮
Renee
杰克的情况我听说了
I heard about Jack.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我还在听杰克的报告
I'm still debriefing him but I brought a full
拿到了毒气罐的具体细节描述
Description of the canisters.
好的
All right.
好的 传给外勤探员们
All right,get this out to the field agents.
他怎么样了
How's he doing?
很难说
Hard to tell.
拉里  今天太多的人为此付出了生命
Larry,so many people have died today.
我们不能让他们白白牺牲啊
We cannot let their deaths be for nothing
不会的
we won't.
拉里  托尼·阿尔梅达
Larry. I've got Tony Almeida
-在线上  -阿尔梅达
- On the phone. - Almeida?
他说他现在在斯塔克伍德内部
He says he's calling from inside Starkwood.
接过来
Put him through.
托尼请讲
Go ahead,Tony.
你是谁
Who am I talking to?
拉里·莫斯  怎么回事
It's Larry Moss. what's going on?
我在斯塔克伍德基地里
I am in Starkwood compound.
被一个叫乔纳斯·霍奇斯的人抓住了
I was being held by a man named Jonas Hodges,
但我被他的一个手下放了
But i was released by one of his executives.
他叫格雷格·西顿
A man named Greg seaton.
现在他想和我们达成一个协议
Now he wants to cut a deal.
他想要豁免权
He wants immunity.
他能提供些什么情报
What's he offering in return?
他知道武器的藏匿地点
He knows where the weapons are being held.
好的  托尼  我要向总统汇报
All right,Tony,I got to run this by the president.
等一下  拉里
Wait,Larry.
杰克怎么样了
Do you know what happened to Jack?
他在调查局
He's here.
在医务室
He's in medical.
-他中枪了吗  -不是
- Was he hit? - no.
有一个毒气罐泄露了
One of the canisters was breached.
他被感染了
He's been infected.
托尼  我要联系白宫了  你做好准备
Tony,I got to call the White House. stand by.
詹尼斯  在会议室设好白宫和阿尔梅达的
Janis,set up a secure connection in the conference
安全连接  准备好接受总统的签字确认
Room with Almeida and the White House for this signature.
帮我联系总统
And get me the president on the phone.
这是什么
What is this?
一盘从桑加拉找回来的录像带
Footage recovered from Sangala.
该录像带是45分钟前从一残存的
It was smuggled out of the remains
生化武器实验室偷带出来的
Of a biological weapons lab about 45 minutes ago.
现在可以确认了
It's a confirmation that Juma was experimenting
朱玛在自己人身上试验生化武器
With biological weapons on the local population.
这些可怜的人遭受着
These poor people were suffering
军用级朊病毒变体的毒害
From the effects of the weaponized prion variant.
这就是我们让斯塔克伍德
And that's what we allowed Starkwood
带到这个国家的东西
To bring into this country.
这可不能算我们的错
We didn't allow this.
斯塔克伍德是我们亲手造就的魔鬼
Starkwood is a monster we created,Olivia.
这几年来我们一直优待他
We have been feeding it for years.
给他们军队合约
We gave them military contracts.
我们信赖他们的雇佣兵
We relied on their paid mercenaries
胜过自己的军队
Instead of our own soldiers,
外包给他们情报收集任务
Outsourced intelligence gathering operations.
上帝啊  我们甚至出台了一部法律
My god,we even passed a law
让他们可以在首都华盛顿
So that they could build a military base
仅仅13公里远的地方建造军事基地
13 miles from the nation's capitol.
您上任以来一直是对他们持反对态度的
You fought against all that.
你一直想限制斯塔克伍德的势力膨胀
You've been trying to limit Starkwood's power Ever since you took office.
我做的还不够
I didn't do enough...
还不及时
Fast enough.
现在可能太晚了
And now it may be too late.
总统阁下  蒂姆·伍兹
Madam president,tim woods
和斯密斯上校要见您
And admiral smith are here to see you.
-让他们进来吧  -是  阁下
- Send them in.  - Yes,ma'am.
总统阁下  调查局的拉里·莫斯在线
Madam president,Larry Moss at FBI is calling in.
他说事态紧急
He says it's urgent.
接过来
Put him through.
莫斯探员  总统就在这  请讲
Agent Moss,the president's here. go ahead.
总统阁下  一个在斯塔克伍德的人
Madam president,we've been contacted
刚刚联系了我们
By someone inside Starkwood.
是托尼·阿尔梅达
Ma'am,it's Tony Almeida.
阿尔梅达
Almeida?
他一直在协助鲍尔夺回那些武器
He's been working with Jack Bauer to recover these weapons.
他被俘之后
He was taken captive but then released
又被一个内部人员放了
By someone on the inside.
他叫格雷格·西顿
His name is Greg seaton.
他是乔纳斯·霍奇手下的核心成员
He's part of Jonas Hodges' inner circle.
他想告诉我们武器的位置
Ma'am,he says he's willing to tell us
来交换豁免权
Where the weapons are in exchange for immunity.
我已开始为定点突袭作部署
Now,I've already started mobilizing for a targeted raid.
我们可以打他们个措手不及
We can catch 'em by surprise
夺回这些武器
And lock down these weapons.
但需要您签署一份对西顿的豁免协议
But i'm going to need you to sign an immunity agreement for this man.
西顿的这个情报  你觉得可靠吗
How confident are you of seaton's intel?
千真万确  阁下
We believe it's genuine,ma'am.
总统阁下
Madam president,
机不可失  时不再来啊
We may not get a chance like this again.
史密斯上将你觉得呢
Admiral smith?
我也这么认为
I concur
我还建议给局里一支海豹突击队作为后援
But I would suggest we supplement the FBI With a seal squad.
只要我一声令下  即刻出发
They're ready to move on my order.
司法部长看到我们在行动中出动部队
The attorney general will raise hell
肯定会不依不饶
About us involving the military in this operation.
待会再说他吧
We'll deal with him later.
莫斯探员
Agent Moss,you have
我直接授权你进攻斯塔克伍德
My direct authorization to move on Starkwood.
什么时候能准备好
How soon can you be ready?
我们已经通过网讯公司
We've already drafted an executive pardon,
上传了刚刚起草的一份豁免书
And set it up via webex.
等您的电子签名一到  我们就可以出发了
You'll be able to give a secure digital signature and we are good to go.
文件在您助理的电脑上
We have the document set up at your assistant's computer.
莫斯探员  总统准备签了
Agent Moss, the president is prepared to sign.
请签字吧  阁下
Go ahead,ma'am.
好的  可以了
All right,it's done.
托尼  看到签名了吗
Tony,did you get the signature?
嗯  看到了
Yeah,we're good.
什么时候能到达斯塔克伍德
When can you be at Starkwood?
10分钟之内
We can be there in ten minutes.
莫斯探员  谢谢
Agent Moss,thank you.
祝你好运
And good luck.
谢谢  总统阁下
Thank you,ma'am.
出发
Let's go.
总统阁下  我们这次真幸运啊
Madam president,we may have just caught a lucky break.
危机解除之前
Until this plays out,
大家还得继续寻求其他良策
I want everyone to keep looking for other options.
好的  西顿先生
All right,Mr. seaton.
请说吧
Go ahead.
武器在一个仓库里
The weapons are in a warehouse
就在基地的东北角
On the northeast quadrant of the compound.
北纬32度44分23秒
32,44.23 north...
西经117度10分42秒
117,10.42 west.
西顿先生  我们需要有人在地面协助侦查
Mr. seaton,it would help to have someone on the ground doing recon.
你可以把托尼带到仓库那边吗
Can you get Tony to that warehouse?
可以的
I think so.
最好找一个步话机来
See if you can get ahold of a hand radio.
我们在480千赫频段
We'll be on 480 kilohertz.
好的  我们马上就到
All right,we'll be there.
如果我们在这降落  离仓库只有50码
If we land here,we'll be within 50 yards of the warehouse.
后援小组在这和这  给我们作策应
Yeah,support teams here and here. Shore us up.
和海军协同作战
Coordinate with the navy.
开始行动  我们楼上见
Get moving. I'll meet you upstairs.
出发
Let's move!
你们在调兵遣将  发生什么事了
You're mobilizing. what's going on?
我们接到托尼的电话
We got a call from Tony.
他和斯塔克伍德的一个内应一起行动
He's working with an informant inside Starkwood.
我们知道武器的位置了
We got a location on the weapon,
-我们正准备派部队进行突袭  -我想去
- We're getting ready to stage a raid on the compound.  - I want to go.
我能理解你的动机  但很抱歉
I can understand why,but i'm sorry.
-我不会批准  -拉里  我能帮上忙
- I can't allow it. - Larry,i can help you with this.
我是唯一见过毒气罐的人
I'm the only one who's seen the canisters,
我知道它什么样
I know exactly what we're looking for.
我看了你的简报  你把所需细节都说了
I read your debrief. You gave us all the details we need.
拉里  拜托了  我有权去
Larry,please,i've earned this.
杰克  我清楚你今天所立下的汗马功劳
Jack,i know what you've done today,
还有你所付出的巨大牺牲
The sacrifice you've made.
在其他任何情况下
Uh,under any other circumstances,
我会让你和大家并肩作战  但你被感染了
I'd want you out there with us,but you're sick,
我们不知道  你什么时候会发作
And we have no idea when you're going to start showing sympToms.
我不能在行动中冒这个险
I cannot risk that happening out in the field.
这次行动需要精兵强将
I need my best men for this operation.
我希望你能理解
I hope you can understand that.
你是对的
You're right.
我一直坚信最终我们会有达成一致的地方
I always knew eventually we'd agree on something.
我很抱歉  杰克
I'm so sorry,Jack.
西顿先生吗
Mr. Seaton?
墨菲  我需要查一下人员
Murphy,i need To check the personnel that...
就在那
That's it.
武器都在里面
The weapons are inside there.
里面有多少人
How many men inside?
霍奇斯  武器押运小队  保安
Hodges,munitions team,security.
怎么也得12个以上吧
I'm guessing a dozen or more.
形势逼人啊  汤米
Wolves are at the door,Tommy.
还要多久
How much longer?
武器部署完还需一小时  先生
We're still an hour away from being armed,sir.
我们刚截获了政府的通讯
We just intercepted a government transmission.
联邦调查局的人正杀将过来
FBI is on the way.
先生  我们连序列检查都没完成呢
Sir,we haven't even run the sequence checks yet.
快马加鞭吧
Let's do it!
该死
Oh,damn it.
还要多久能到
What's our ETA?
2分钟  长官
Two minutes,sir.
托尼  我是拉里·莫斯
Tony,it's Larry Moss.
你到达位置了吗
Are you in position?
是的
Affirmative.
我们在仓库北边约50码外
We're about 50 yards north of the warehouse.
有什么发现
What can you tell me?
南北各有一个入口
Got two entrances,north and south.
铁门很结实
Heavy steel doors.
两个带自动武器的警卫
Two guards armed with auTomatic weapons.
西顿说里面可能有十二个左右的人
Seaton says there's probably about a dozen inside.
他们应该也都带着武器
We have to assume they're armed,as well.
好的  我们就快到了
All right. we're almost there.
我需要你监视地面上的动静
I'm gonna need your eyes on the ground,
以防有人阻止我们降落
in case there's any resistance.
收到
Copy that.
空中一号呼叫总部
Aerial one to home base.
目标已确认  我们准备
Target has been confirmed. we are go
-按A计划行事  -收到  空中一号
- For tac plan alpha.  - copy that,aerial one.
视频监控已打开  我们在监控你的行动
All feeds are live. we're monitoring your approach.
斯塔克伍德空塔向我们发信号
Sir,we're being signaled by Starkwood's air tower.
让我和他们对话
Let me talk to them.
连上了
You're on.
我是联邦调查局探员拉里·莫斯
This is special agent Larry Moss from FBI.
我们奉美国总统之命
We have an executive order from the president of the United States
来搜查你们其中一栋建筑
To search one of your buildings.
调查局吗  我需要从我上级那得到许可
FBI? i'll need to get authorization from my superior.
我们已把命令的电子副本发给你了
We have sent you a digital copy of the executive order.
查一下你的无线频率
Check your wireless frequency.
这就是你所需要的授权
That is all the authorization you will need.
不要试图阻挠  否则你将会被逮捕
Make no attempt to interfere,or you will be arrested.
明白吗
Do you understand?
明白  调查局
Understood,FBI.
带我们进去
Take us in.
空中一号呼叫总部
Aerial one to home base.
我们准备降落
We're good to go.
收到   空中一号
Copy that,aerial one.
看来你的行动顺利
Looks like you have got a clean approach.
没有发现敌情
No hostiles in sight.
你没事吧
You all right?
我们带了医生
We have a medic.
我没事
I'm fine.
西顿  你跟在我们后面
Seaton,i need you to stay behind us.
出发
Let's go.
放下武器
Stand down!
叫你们放下武器
You were told to stand down!
放下武器  趴在地上
Lower your weapons and get on the ground now!
看住他们
Lock them down!
门是锁着的  长官
Locked,sir.
炸开它
Blow it.
准备爆破
Blasting!
3 2 1
Three. two. one!
上  上
Go. go!
武器在哪里
Where are the weapons?
我不知道
I don't know.
你什么意思
What do you mean,you don't know?
阿尔梅达威胁说要杀我
Almeida was threatening to kill me.
我只好编他想听的告诉他
I told him what he wanted to hear.
你这狗娘养的骗子   是你主动来找我的
You lying son of a bitch! you came to me!
武器在哪里
Now,where are the weapons?!
武器到底在哪里
Where are the damn weapons?!
叫他把手拿开
tell him to take his hand off me
托尼  托尼  你退下
Tony? Tony! i need you to stand down now!
你跑不掉的
You're not getting away with this.
押起来
Secure him!
他在撒谎  拉里
He's lying,Larry.
他耍了我
He played me.
我知道  看出来了
Yeah,i know. it looks that way.
看到了吧
Well,what do you know?
西顿老弟给我们争取到了一点时间
Little old seaton bought us some time.
他们在基地的另一边
They're on the other side of the compound.
我们只要把他们困在那就成了
We just have to keep them there.
这里什么都没有  长官
There's nothing here,sir.
蕾妮  我们扑空了
Renee,the warehouse is empty.
托尼的内应把我们带到了错误的地点
Tony's informant sent us to the wrong location.
整件事就是个骗局
This whole thing was a diversion.
他们不可能转移那么快
They couldn't have gotten them out that fast.
武器还藏在基地的某个地方
The weapons are there somewhere.
拉里  武器一定还在斯塔克伍德基地中
Larry,the weapons have to be inside of Starkwood.
让他们继续搜寻
Tell them to keep looking.
原地待命
Stand by.
好  都出去
All right,everyone outside now.
好  听着
All right,listen up.
我们要在整个基地中做地毯式搜查
We're going to do a point-by-point search of this entire compound.
好的
Good.
四支小队搜查这里的每栋建筑
I want four teams sweeping every structure on this property.
杰克
Jack.
别开枪
Hold your fire!
Hold your fire.
别开枪
呆在原地
Stay in position.
让拉里叫他的人放下武器
Tell Larry to have his men stand down.
你开玩笑吧  他们想跟联邦军队动武
Are you kidding me? they just drew on federal forces.
如果你不想你的人白白送死的话
If you don't want to lose your men,you'll get them
就叫他们立刻缴械投降  快
To stand down now. now!
别开枪
Hold your fire!
够了  别再往前了
That's far enough.
我们已配合了你们搜查这仓库的要求
We cooperated with your demand to search this building.
现在  我们要求你们离开
Now,we're asking you to leave.
这里有生化武器
There are biological weapons on this facility.
找不到它们  我们不会走
We're not going anywhere without them.
让你的人退后
Now,tell your men to stand down.
这种诬陷太荒谬了
Those charges are absurd,
我们不会让你们继续搜索的
And we're not going to let you keep searching.
这里是私人领地
You're on private property,
如有必要  我们会奋起反击
And we're prepared to defend it if necessary.
你在威胁联邦探员
You are threatening federal agents.
马上给我退后
Stand down! now!
我们在维护自己的权利
We're protecting our rights
我们不会让一个充满敌意的政府
Against a hostile government that's using
用莫须有的罪名来关闭我们的基地
False charges to try to shut us down.
我们不想兵刃相见
Now,we don't want any bloodshed.
但如果你们得寸进尺
But if you try to advance any farther,
我们会开枪还击
You will be fired upon.